<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2020">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
	<title>Installing the redBorder Enterprise Edition IPS</title>
    <section>
		<title>What is an IDS?</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">IDS</emphasis> is an Intrusion Detection System to protect one or more organization network.</para> 
		<para>It is a specific software that runs in the user space and analyze network traffic (using a mirror port or SPAN) in one system interface or between two interfaces joined as a bridge (software switch).</para>
		<para>The traffic is analyzed looking for anomalies, specific signatures or suspicious behavior.</para> 
		<para>The goal of an IDS is <emphasis role="bold">to dectect intrusions and create alerts without interfering with the organization's traffic.</emphasis></para>
    </section>
    <section>
		<title>What is an IPS?</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">IPS</emphasis> is an Intrusion Prevention System that works in the network or networks inside an organization.</para> 
		<para>It works in the same way as an IDS (in fact, it is usually the same software with an adapted behavior), except that in this case it does interfere with the organization's traffic,
		 in that way when an attack is detected the system can choose between 
		 <emphasis role="bold">showing alerts or even discard the packets, creating the same effect as a firewall.</emphasis></para>
		 <para>The configuration and registration of the IPS/IDS sensors into the Manager is the next step to the installation one. This process consists in two steps:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Installation and registration of the IPS/IDS sensors in the Manager</para>							
			</listitem>	
			<listitem>
				<para>Configuration of basic parameters of the IPS/IDS sensors in the redborder platform</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section>
	    <title>Requirements</title>
	    <para><emphasis role = "bold">redBorder IPS</emphasis> is a software that needs the following requirements in order to function correctly. The minimum essential elements required for the installation as well as those recommended for correct performance are referenced at every SNORT instance being executed. They are shown in the following table:</para>
		<mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit = "1" align = "center" width = "350" fileref ="images/ch01_img001.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
				<phrase> Figure 1: Requirements for installing redBorder IPS</phrase>
            </textobject>
            <caption>
                <para> Figure 1: Requirements for installing redBorder IPS </para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
		<para> For example, if you want four SNORT instances in the recommended configuration, you need a machine with 16 GB and four cores.</para>
                <warning>
                  <title> Warning </title>
                  <para> It is VERY IMPORTANT that the configuration of the Manager (or cluster of managers) is performed before configuring IPS sensors. </para>
                  <para> The Manager must be operational and in a network accessible to the sensors. Some of the sensor configuration processes depend on the access to the Manager. </para>
                </warning>
	</section>	
	<section>
		<title>Obtaining the ISO</title>
		<para> Redborder Enterprise Edition IPS is distributed as an ISO file that can be obtained in different ways. If you don’t have it, please contact our sales team (sales@redborder.com) or our support team (support@redborder.com) to provide you with the last available ISO file or a way to download it.</para>
	</section>	
	<section>
		<title>Burning the ISO Image</title>
		<para> The ISO image is prepared to perform the boot from a DVD reader, USB device or as an ISO file for a virtual machine.</para>
		<para><emphasis role = "bold">NOTE: The process of creating a bootable USB for the IPS installation is the same as for the manager installation. You can find it accessing the support page.</emphasis></para>
		<para>In order to burn the ISO image from a Linux system to a USB device, the following command needs to be used if the USB device is mapped in /dev/sdd:</para>
		<programlisting>[root@machine ~]# dd if=redBorder-3.1.XX-XX-x86_64-6.5-sensor.iso of=/dev/sdd bs=10M</programlisting>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Replace XX-XX in redBorder-3.1.<emphasis>XX-XX</emphasis>-x86_64-6.5-sensor.iso by the patched version of the redborder 3.1 that you have, for example: redBorder-3.1.80-18-x86_64-6.5-sensor.iso.</para>
		</note>
	</section>	
	<section>
		<title>Installing the ISO</title>
		<warning>
			<title> Warning </title>
			<para>If a usb memory is used on a real machine, the operating system will be automatically extending the disk and the data on the usb will be lost. To avoid this, the usb needs to be removed before rebooting.</para>
		</warning>
		<para>Once you have booted the redborder ISO, you will see the installation menu. To perform the installation, select the option: Install Sensor IPS:</para>
		<mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit = "1" align = "center" width = "450" fileref ="images/ch01_img002.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
				<phrase>Figure 2: Installation process</phrase>
            </textobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Figure 2: Installation process</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
		<para>Once in the installation process, the user only needs to confirm the installation destination and root password. Redborder is prepared for unattended installations and so you should be especially careful with the time you have to respond to these three questions if you wish to modify the default options:</para>
		<mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit = "1" align = "center" width = "450" fileref ="images/ch01_img003.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
				<phrase>Figure 3: Installation process</phrase>
            </textobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Figure 3: Installation process</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
		<para>Once this page has been confirmed, the installation will carry out all of the necessary processes to prepare the system for configuration.</para>
	</section>
		<section>
		<title>Basic Configuration</title>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>To make this installation and configuration process it is necessary to login with the user with highest permissions: <emphasis>root.</emphasis></para>
		</note>	
		<para>Start the configuration manager by executing:</para>
		<programlisting>[root@rbmanager ~]# rb_sysconf</programlisting>
		<mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit = "1" align = "center" width = "450" fileref ="images/ch01_img005.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
				<phrase>Figure 5: Basic Configuration</phrase>
            </textobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Figure 5: Basic Configuration</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
		<para>This menu consists of 5 options:</para>
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>System Configuration:</literal> from this option you can define basic settings such as hostname, date, time, etc.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Network Configuration:</literal> this is the option where you can configure the network settings.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Passwords:</literal> access this option if you want to change your passwords.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Update rules from Manager:</literal> select this option to force the download of the Manager rules (optional).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>quit:</literal> exit.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
    </section>
	<section>
        <title>Network configuration</title>
        <para>IDS/IPS sensors need to comunicate with the el Manager, to make this possible it is necessary to make the network configuration. Select option <literal>2) Network Configuration</literal> from the redborder configuration menu.</para>
        <para>Until this setting is not made properly, it will not be possible to register the sensor in the Manager..</para>
        <para>These are the steps you need to follow to configure the network of your sensor:</para>
        <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
            <listitem>
                <para>Management Network Configuration:</para>
                <para>a) Bonding creation and management interface assignment.</para>
                <para>b) Segments configuration.</para>	
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>DNS and domain configuration</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <note>
            <title>Note</title>
            <para>The order to configure the management network can be different. The order indicated in this installation manual is the one considered most optimal.</para>
        </note>
        <warning>
            <title>Warning</title>
            <para>In case that the system is installed on a real computer that has more than one network card, the user must choose which will be the management bonding.</para>
        </warning>
    </section>
	<section>
		<title>Interface assignment and bonding creation</title>
		<para>Select <literal>Network Configuration</literal> typing <keycap>2</keycap> and press <keycap>Enter.</keycap></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img016.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Automatic assignment of segments with bypass</para>
		</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In case the system recognizes interfaces with <emphasis>bypass</emphasis>, these will be automatically assigned to the segments..</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img017.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Network sensor configuration</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>To configure the network configuration correctly:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Bonding creation: (maximum 4 bonds).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Selection and assignment of bonding ports.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Management network interfaces selection for bonding.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>The system will show a list with very valuable and detailed information, which will help the administrator to decide which ports are available for the creation of the bonding.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img018.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Insert bonding port</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Insertar bonding port</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>To select the default options press: <keycap>Enter</keycap></para>
		</note>
    
		<section>
			<title>Creation of a new bonding and port assignment</title>
			<para>To illustrate this process we will create a bonding (bond0) and assign 2 ports to it.</para>
			<para>Select option <keycap>n</keycap> that appears in the submenu on the right side of the screen.</para>
			<para>Once you have reviewed the ports that are available, select the one that you want to assign to bonding, as it appears in the lower margin of the previous screen.</para>
			<para>Enter the port number on the line <literal>Insert bonding first port [0]:</literal></para>
			<para>The number in brackets <literal>[]</literal> it is the one that defines the system by default. To select this number press <keycap>Enter.</keycap></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img019.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Bonding creation: port assignment</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Bonding creation: port assignment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>The selected port will disappear from the available ports list.</para>
			<important>
				<title>Important</title>
				<para>The system only allows a maximum of 4 bonds: (0-3).</para>
			</important>
		</section>
		<section>
				<title>Add a new port to bonding</title>
				<para>The system will ask you the following question: <literal>Insert second port (y/N)</literal></para>
				<para>The default option is displayed in upper case. Remember that if you dont need to add a new port you only need to press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>
				<para>In case you want to insert a new port press <keycap>y</keycap>.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img020.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Add new port to bonding</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add new port to bonding</para>
				</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>Enter the port number on the line <literal>Insert bonding second port [1]:</literal></para>
				<para>The number in brackets <literal>[]</literal> it is the one that defines the system by default. To select this number just press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Bonding network configuration</title>
			<para>Once you have assigned the second port to the new bond (bond0), the system will ask you to enter the following data:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>IP Address</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Network mask</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Gateway</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Routes</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>If your device uses the DHCP protocol, it will be assigned a default IP address. Press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to select the IP, mask and gateway assigned by the system. Otherwise, manually enter these values.</para>
			<para>The system also gives you a default route for the created bonding.</para>
			<para>To insert a route manually, select the option <keycap>y</keycap> on the line <literal>Insert a route for this bonding (y/N)?:</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img021.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
				<para>Manually add a route to the bonding</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once you have finished this process, you will see a message advising you that the Bonding has been successfully created: <literal>Bonding 0 created successfully.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img022.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finish the bonding creation process</title>
			<para>Before applying changes and finishing the bonding creation process, the system will show you a table that shows the newly created bonding (bond0) together with the ports that have been assigned to it, the assigned IP and Mask and the route.</para>	
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Apply changes</emphasis></para>
			<para>To save the settings select option <keycap>a</keycap>.</para>
			<para>You can delete the created bond(s) at any time by selecting the option <literal>delete bonding</literal> pressing the key <keycap>d</keycap>.</para>
			<para>To return to the main network configuration menu, select the option <literal>quit</literal> pressing <keycap>q</keycap>.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>DNS and domain configuration</title>
		<para>In the network configuration menu we find the option <literal>DNS and domain settings.</literal> To start the process, select option<keycap>2</keycap>.</para>
		<para>To perform the configuration correctly, the user must enter:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Domain name</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Primary DNS address</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Secondary DNS address (optional)</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Once this information has been entered, the system will warn that this configuration has been applied correctly.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img023.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>DNS and domain configuration</para>
		</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>To finish the process, it is not necessary to apply changes, select the option <literal>quit</literal> pressing <keycap>q</keycap> to return to the network settings main menu.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Network segments configuration</title>
		<para>Select in the Network Configuration Menu the option <literal>Segment settings</literal> pressing the number <keycap>3</keycap>.</para>
		<para>This screen shows the number of segments that have been created, the ports assigned to each segment and whether or not they have bypass support.</para>
		<para>On this section you will find the following submenu:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>f)</keycap> <literal>force bypass autoassign:</literal> to automatic assignment of ports with bypass.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>n)</keycap> <literal>new segment:</literal> select to create a new segment.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>d)</keycap> <literal>delete segment:</literal> to delete a segment.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>q)</keycap> <literal>quit:</literal>exit.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>To start creating the segment, select the option <literal>n) new segment.</literal></para>
		<para>The segment creation process includes the following actions:</para>
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para>Assignment of bypass interfaces to segments (optional).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Creation a segmenet: (max 16 segments).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Selecting and assigning ports to the segment</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para> In order to select a port, a list with very valuable and detailed information will be displayed, which will help the administrator to decide on which ports the created segments will use.</para>
    
		<section>
			<title>Bypass interfaces selection</title>
			<para>If the system detects bypass interfaces, they are automatically assigned to segments when you enter the network configuration menu.</para>
			<para>There are also two other ways of assigning ports or interfaces with bypass to segments:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold"> Force bypass autoassign:</emphasis> select option <literal>Force bypass auto assign</literal> in the segment configuration menu, entering the letter <keycap>f</keycap>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Manual assignment:</emphasis> selecting the ports with bypass from the list of available ports that will be displayed in the process of creating the segments.</para>				
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img024.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Assign ports to the segment</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating a new segment and assigning ports</title>
			<para>To illustrate this process we will create a segment (segment 0) and assign 2 ports to it.</para>
			<para>To start the segment creation process, select the option <keycap>n</keycap> that appears in the submenu on the right side of the screen.</para>
			<para>Once you have reviewed the ports that are available, select the one you want to assign to the segment as it appears in the lower margin of the previous screen.</para>
			<para>Enter the segment number on the line <literal>Insert segment number (0-15) [0]:</literal></para>
			<para>Th number in brackets <literal>[]</literal> it is the one that defines the system by default. To select this number press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>
			<para>The port previously assigned to the segment will disappear from the list of available ports.</para>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>The system only allows the creation of a maximum of 16 segments (0-15).</para>
			</note>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Add a second port to the segmentt</title>
			<para>Once you have assigned the first port to the segment, the system will ask you to assign a second port: <literal>Assign second port to the segment (Y/n):</literal></para>
			<para>The default option is displayed in upper case.</para>
			<para>Remember that if you want to assign a new port you only have to press the key <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>
			<para>In case you dont want to assign a new port, type <keycap>n</keycap>. Select an available port from the list.</para>
			<para>Enter the port number on the line <literal>Insert segment second port [3]:</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img025.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Assign a new port to the segment</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once both ports have been assigned to a segment, the system will notify you that the segment has been successfully created: <literal>Segment 0 created successfully.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img026.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Segment creation confirmation</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finish the process of creating the segments</title>
			<para>Before applying changes and finishing the segment creation process, you will see a screen with a list that includes the following elements:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>Segments</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Ports assigned to the segment</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Whether or not it has bypass support</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img027.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Summary of assigned segments and ports</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>		
			<para>You can delete in any moment the created segments by selection <literal>delete segment</literal>, pressing  <keycap>d</keycap>.</para>
			<para>To return to the main network configuration menu, select the option <literal>quit</literal> by pressing <keycap>q</keycap>.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img028.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Segments overview</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Apply changes</emphasis></para>
			<para>To save the settings press <keycap>a.</keycap></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch01_img029.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Apply changes to finish segment creation process</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>		
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>		
